CHRIS PRITCHARD

• DETAILS •

07597144220 cee.pritchard@gmail.com

LINKS

<u>LinkedIn</u>

SKILLS

Good team player

Leadership Skills

Good Communication

Customer Care

High Attention to Detail

HOBBIES

Software Programming and
Development (Python, HTML, CSS,
JavaScript)
Graphic Design (Adobe Suite of
Products)
Mobile Application Design (Flutter

and Dart)

PROFILE

Enthusiastic and experienced IT sales Account Manager, specialising in networking and storage solutions with over 10 years experience in IT distribution.

Regularly achieved and exceeded KPI's, having achieved over £1m+ profit in a single financial year.

Highly client orientated with experience in building relationships from C-level down.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sales Lead at Lavender and Lime (Self-Employed), UK and Canada

May 2016 — January 2022

Self-owned business focusing on alternative health and wellness products.

Responsible for growing customer base, repeat sales into existing customers as well as recruiting new salespeople to join the team.

Design and generation of promotional and educational materials using the Adobe suite of products.

Extensive presentation, both in-person and online to generate new sales as well as educate existing customers.

Group Product Manager - Fortinet at Zycko Group, Cirencester

October 2015 — May 2016

Responsible for the Fortinet Meru product range within the Zycko group.

Liaising with all links within the distribution chain from Vendor through to End User.

Assisted in creating excel based tools to make quotation easier for the distribution sales team, including automated calculation of rebate schemes.

Major Account Manager at Zycko Limited, Cirencester

October 2012 — October 2015

Responsible for the Account Directorship of the company's single largest reseller, delivering year on year growth of the account with delivery of over £1m+ profit in a single financial year.

Maintaining relationships from C-level down, I regularly achieved and exceeded set targets.

Account Manager at Zycko Limited, Cirencester

April 2007 — October 2012

Responsible for Day-to-Day Account Management of a portfolio of Resellers.

Delivery of full solution sales with specialism in Storage and WAN optimisation technologies, as well as other networking hardware.

EDUCATION

BA(Hons) Music Industry Management, Buckinghamshire New University, High Wycombe

1997 - 2000

Business degree with application to the Music Industry.

Graduated with a 2:2

A-Levels, Colchester Sixth Form College, Colchester September 1994 — June 1996 Philosophy - C French - D Music - D GCSE Spanish - B GCSE, The Honywood school, Coggeshall September 1989 — June 1994 9 GCSE A-C including English Language, English Literature and Mathematics REFERENCES **Gordon Lyon from Nuvias UK** gordon.lyon@nuvias.com · 01285 868500 **Joe Carlos** Carlos21@outlook.com · 07775 625211 **COURSES** Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python, MITx June 2021 — August 2021

Flutter & Dart - The Complete Guide, Udemy

March 2021 — May 2021